Gurgaon, India +91-7678531648 chaarvib@gmail.com

# Chaarvi Bansal

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u> Personal website

#### **SUMMARY**

I am pre-final year student at BITS Pilani. I am interested in Deep Learning and Biocomputation. I spend my time working on a selection of projects to improve my current skill-set. I have developed a passion for science and I am interested in pursuing independent research as an undergraduate.

### **EDUCATION**

Dual Degree: Master of Science - Biological Sciences, Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science

Aug 2018 — May 2023

Birla Institute of Technology and Science Pilani, India

CGPA: 8.98/10

**INSPIRE-SHE Scholar:** Secured the coveted scholarship by The Department of Science and Technology (Govt. of India) for finishing in the **top** 1% in All India Senior School Certificate Examination 2018 and maintaining outstanding academic record in college.

#### **RELEVANT COURSEWORK**

**Computer Science:** Neural Networks and Fuzzy Logic (Ongoing), Object Oriented Programming in Java, Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Computer Programming in C

**Biological Sciences:** Biomolecular Modelling (Ongoing), Stem Cell and Regenerative Biology (Ongoing), Bioinformatics, Recombinant DNA Technology, Biophysics, Genetics, Cell Biology, Biochemistry

Mathematics: Probability and Statistics, Linear Algebra, Multivariate Calculus

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language C, C++, Java, Python

Frameworks Skicit-learn, Pytorch (Beginner), Tensorflow (Beginner)

Tools MySQL, GIT

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Researcher | Advanced Data Analytics and Parallel Technologies Lab, BITS Pilani

Jan 2021 — Present

Project: Hybrid DE-NOVO Genome Assembler

Advisor - Dr. Poonam Goyal

- Implemented a two-level hash table structure to reduce the retrieval time and to make the algorithm easy to distribute and parallelize.
- Devised a maximum voting algorithm to increase the intermediate assembly length by 30%.
- · Working on error-handling algorithm and exploring the applications of machine learning in contig generation problem.

Summer Research Intern | North Eastern Space Application Center, Govt. of India

May 2020 - Jun 2020

Project: QAi Toolbox: QGIS Plugin for Machine Learning and Deep Learning based Land Cover Classification

Advisor: Mr. Nilay Nishant

Government research lab serving eight states of India's North Eastern Region using space science and technology.

- Developed three advanced land cover classification models for integration with QGIS through a plugin (QAi Toolbox).
- Achieved a kappa score of **0.81** on pixel-based models and accuracy of **94.46**% on CNN-based image segmentation models.
- QAi Toolbox was selected amongst the top 30 worldwide for presentation at QGIS North America 2020, an annual international
  conference conducted by OSGeo.

Undergraduate Researcher | Bioinformatics Lab, BITS Pilani

Project: MiRNA and Acquisition of Drug Resistance in Cancer Cells

Jan 2020 — May 2020

Advisor - Dr. Rajdeep Chowdhury

- Analysed deep sequencing data of osteosarcoma cells in four different stages.
- Identified deregulated miRNA-mRNA sets responsible for the development of drug resistance to cisplatin.
- Studied and examined the impact of miRNA deregulation on cellular processes.

## **LEADERS**HIP POSITIONS

## Joint Coordinator, Tinkering Lab, BITS Pilani

Jan 2021 — Present

Tinkering Lab will be a fully student-driven, 24x7 open makerspace to promote learning by doing.

- · Leading a team of six members to establish a multi-domain research facility at BITS Pilani for 5000+ students.
- Scope of work includes but is not limited to ideation, formulation, financial allocations, execution, and operations.
- Engineered five different programs to foster the entrepreneurial capability and instill a sense of social responsibility.